# **Chris Agnew**

Conneaut, OH • 540-369-5299 • chris.agnew@pm.me • linkedin.com/in/chris-agnew12 • https://chrisagnew.codes

## **Full Stack Developer**

Experienced Full-Stack Developer with 4+ years of expertise. Proficient in Shopify, Next.js, React, Node.js, and Tailwind CSS. Improved website performance, achieving a 50% increase in speed and a 150% boost in annual online sales in just 9 months. Reduced file sizes by 90% and prevented \$2.4 million in annual losses in 6 months.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Central Garden and Pet • 02/2023 - Present

Remote

#### E-Commerce and Marketing Web Developer (TDBBS Brands)

- » Served as the main technical expert for web-related challenges, debugging, and ensuring uninterrupted online operations
- » Optimized JavaScript and Shopify Liquid code, leading to a 100% improvement in site speed and performance in 3 days, enhancing user experience and higher conversion rates.
- » Executed website optimization to meet WCAG standards in just 3 weeks, boosting user engagement and ensuring inclusivity for all visitors.
- » Implemented a new strategy for uploading media using image compression and file type to reduce file size by 90%.
- » Established a protective solution that prevented \$2.4 million in annual losses in 6 months, securing the company's monetary resources

# Chris Agnew LLC • 06/2020 - Present

Remote

#### Freelance Web Developer

- » Freelancer Full-Stack JavaScript/TypeScript developer with consistent use of Next.js/React, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, and various Headless CMS platforms.
- » Developed and launched 26 new website features, enhancing user experience and increasing customer satisfaction for previous employer Advanced RV in 2 months
- » Built headless websites and apps using Next.js and Tailwind CSS and CMS while maintaining 100% test coverage

# Advanced RV LLC • 10/2021 - 11/2022

On-Site

#### Software Developer & E-commerce Lead

- » Improved website performance by 50% by implementing a headless website using Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, and Contentful CMS, resulting in a 50% decrease in bounce rate
- » Led e-commerce team to achieve a 150% profit increase in Shopify sales in 9 months
- » Developed a PTO Tracker App with Google App Script, focusing on automating processes to enhance efficiency before engineering a better solution with TypeScript, TW CSS, and Firebase

### Intellitronix • 08/2019 - 04/2020

On-Site

#### **Shipping & Purchasing Manager**

» Created a new system for Shipping Department processes which resulted in getting promoted on my second day on the job and increased shipping efficiency by 50%.

» Reduced shipping materials costs by 80% through strategic supplier negotiations, resulting in significant cost savings and improved operational efficiency.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js

Frameworks/Libraries: Next.js, Tailwind CSS, React.js, Bootstrap, Shopify, Material UI, Tailwind UI, Prisma,

Styled Components, Chakra UI, Framer Motion, Next SEO

Databases: Firebase, Supabase, PostgreSQL

Testing: Unit Testing, Cypress Testing, E2E Testing

**Tools:** Version Control (Git), GitHub, Github Actions, CI/CD, Jira, Content Management Systems (CMS),

Hosting, Vercel

Hard Skills: Software Development, Static Site Generation (SSG), WCAG and ADA Compliance, User

Interface (UI/UX), Google Search Expert, Process Automation, Server-Side Rendering (SSR)

Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Following Industry Trends, Collaborative

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Lakeland Community College**

Some College in Film, Video Production • GPA: 4.0

Kirtland, Ohio

# **Ohio Virtual Academy**

High School Diploma Maumee, OH